Guide to the Jacob Gould Schurman papers, 1867-1942 [1986].
Schurman, Jacob Gould papers, 1867-1942 [1986].
- Series II. Schurman Articles, Speeches, And Books, 1875-1941 (Reel 48-51)
  - "President Taft's Peace Treaties: A Forward Step in Civilization", 7 Nov. 1911 (Box 9, Folder 51)
  - "Public Opinion and the National Reserve Association Plan", 21-25 Nov. 1911 (Box 9, Folder 52)
  - Quotes from Schurman's speeches on a southern tour., 28 Nov. 1911 (Box 9, Folder 53)
  - Address by Schurman to protest against Russia's treatment of United States passports., 6 Dec. 1911 (Box 9, Folder 54)
  - "Current Unrest and Proposed Remedies", 17 Dec. 1911 (Box 9, Folder 55)
  - Address to the Cornell Socialist Club: "Socialism appeals successfully to two classes of the community...", 14 Jan. 1912 (Box 9, Folder 56)
  - "Socialism" in the New York Tribune., 25 Feb. 1912 (Box 9, Folder 57)
  - Address before Citizens' Mass Meeting in Support of President Taft, Philadelphia., 11 Apr. 1912 (Box 9, Folder 58)
  - Speech on the occasion of the inauguration of Dr. Hibben as President of Princeton University., 11 May 1912 (Box 9, Folder 59)
  - Address to graduating class., 13 June 1912 (Box 9, Folder 60)
  - "Banking Reform and Party Politics", 1912 (Box 9, Folder 61)
  - "Faculty Participation in University Government" from the President's Report., 1912 (Box 9, Folder 62)
  - Notes: "Delighted to be back in America...", 25 Sept. 1913 (Box 9, Folder 63)
  - Address at the laying of the cornerstone, Young Men's Christian Association, Watertown, NY., 21 Oct. 1913 (Box 9, Folder 64)
  - Address at the New York State Conference on Religion., 10-11 Nov. 1913 (Box 9, Folder 65)
  - "Speech" from the publication of the Republican State Convention., 1913 (Box 9, Folder 66)
  - Remarks introducing Ludwig Fulda., 12 Nov. 1913 (Box 9, Folder 67)
  - "The Situation in the Balkans from October 1912 to October 1913" from the Cornell Alumni News., 13 Nov. 1913 (Box 9, Folder 68)
  - "The University's Life and Problems" from the Cornell Alumni News., 5 Feb. 1914 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - "Reforms in State Government", 4 June 1914 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - "Commencement Address" from the Official Publications of Cornell University., 17 June 1914 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - "Commencement Address" from the Cornell Alumni News., 25 June 1914 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Address to Students., 24 Sept. 1914 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - "Annual Address" in the Cornell Alumni News., 1 Oct. 1914 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - "Some Issues of the Day", 13 Nov. 1914 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - "President Schurman Believes Every College Should Introduce Military Training", ca. 1914 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - "Our Colleges and Universities and the National Defense", Dec. 1914 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - "The Prospects of the United States", 21 Dec. 1914 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - "The Outlook for the United States"(A speech also titled "Business and Government"), 21 Dec. 1914 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - "Chemistry in America and Our National Needs", 13 Mar. 1915 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - "Some Problems of the Constitutional Convention" including "Woman Suffrage", 10 Apr. 1915 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - "Address" in the publication of the Delegates of the New York State Constitutional Convention., 10 Apr. 1915 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Address at the Lawyers' Club of Buffalo in Honor of the Delegates of the New York State Constitutional Convention", 10 Apr. 1915 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Address at the Annual Grant dinner of the Unconditional Republican Club in Albany., 28 Apr. 1915 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - "The Cornell of Today" in Cornell Reunion, 1895., 17 May 1915 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Commencement address., 1915 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - "The Cornellian Council is the organized agency...", Sept. 1915 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - "Annual Address" in the Cornell Alumni News., 7 Oct. 1915 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Schoellkopf Field dedication."To All Members of the Instructing Staff", 9 Oct. 191510 Nov. 1915 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Remarks at Founder's Day Exercises., 11 Jan. 1916 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Remarks on Morse Hall fire., Jan. 1916 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - "Speech" in the publication of the Lincoln Dinner., 12 Feb. 1916 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Speech at the Civic Club of Brooklyn: "International Relations", 14 Apr. 1916 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Statements regarding the nomination of a presidential candidate by the Republican party., 17 Apr. 1916 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - "Hughes and the Presidency", Apr. 1916 (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - "Hughes - Why?" in The Independent., 29 May 1916 (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - "Cornell and Military Service", 18 June 1916 (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Address in Stadium: "We open two weeks later than usual: why? Infantile Paralysis...", 12 Oct. 1916 (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - Address at the inauguration of John Balcom Shaw as President of Elmira College., 29 Nov. 1916 (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - "Wilson's Mexican Failure", 1916 (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - "The Outlook for College Women" from the Elmira College Bulletin., Jan. 1917 (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - Interview transcript: "Severance of diplomatic relations does not mean war...", 3 Feb. 1917 (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - "Washington: Then and Now", 22 Feb. 1917 (Box 10, Folder 35)
  - "Oration" in Proceedings of 'University Day,' University of Pennsylvania., 22 Feb. 1917 (Box 10, Folder 36)
  - Remarks at Convocation Hour., 5 Mar. 1917 (Box 10, Folder 37)
  - "Washington: Then and Now" in the Alumni Register - University of Pennsylvania., Mar. 1917 (Box 10, Folder 38)
  - "Agricultural Preparedness", 6 Apr. 1917 (Box 10, Folder 39)
  - "The Present Crisis", 23 Apr. 1917 (Box 10, Folder 40)
  - "Professor Creighton as Teacher", Apr. 1917 (Box 10, Folder 41)
  - Address delivered at the Officers' Training Camp, Madison Barracks., 30 May 1917 (Box 10, Folder 42)
  - "Why America is in the War", 30 May 1917 (Box 10, Folder 43)
  - Notes regarding Germany., 10 June 1917 (Box 10, Folder 44)
  - Address at the Baptist Church: "I think this war, as has been said, was inevitable...", 10 June 1917 (Box 10, Folder 45)
  - Commencement Address., 27 June 1917 (Box 10, Folder 46)
  - "To the Students Actual and Prospective, of Cornell University and the Parents and Guardians of Students", Aug. 1917 (Box 10, Folder 47)
  - "Executive Responsibility for State Government in the Proposed Constitution for New York", 1917 (Box 10, Folder 48)
  - Address before the New York State Woman Suffrage Party Mass Meeting of the Conference at Saratoga Springs: "We live amid the most momentous events that have ever taken place on this planet...", 30 Aug. 1917 (Box 10, Folder 49)
  - Remarks in Cornell Alumni News., 4 Oct. 1917 (Box 10, Folder 50)
  - "It is not for outsiders to interfere with the domestic problems of Columbia University...", 11 Oct. 1917 (Box 10, Folder 51)
  - "President Schurman of Cornell Believes Every College Should Introduce Military Training", 1917 (Box 10, Folder 52)
  - "Some Notes on Balkan Problems", 31 Dec. 1917 (Box 10, Folder 53)
  - Memorandum supplementary to "Some Notes on Balkan Problems", 28 Jan. 1918 (Box 10, Folder 54)
  - Address before the New York State Wholesale Bakers' Association: "The great world-war in which a sufficiency of bread may be the determining factor...", 23 Jan. 1918 (Box 10, Folder 55)
  - Memorandum concerning a conference held with President Wilson by Lawrence Lowell and William H. Taft., 1918 (Box 10, Folder 56)
  - Memorandum of conference with President Wilson., 28 Mar. 1918 (Box 10, Folder 57)
  - "The Food Crisis and the Farmer", 1918 (Box 10, Folder 58)
  - "The Bakers and Food Control", Mar. 1918 (Box 10, Folder 59)
  - Address delivered on the Steamer "Lapland" in Mid-Ocean., 4 July 1918 (Box 10, Folder 60)
  - Commencement Address; Notes on Germany., 23 May 1918 (Box 10, Folder 61)
  - Portion of address at Milk and Dairy Farm Exposition: "At the present time ships are the limiting factor in winning the war...", 23 May 1918 (Box 10, Folder 62)
  - Partial typescript: "With violent fluctuations in demand for different agricultural products...", 1918 (Box 10, Folder 63)
  - "The Time Has Arrived When - ", 8 June 1918 (Box 10, Folder 64)
  - Notes: "Lunched today with Mr. Jacob H. Schiff...", 12 June 1918 (Box 10, Folder 65)
  - Remarks in Cornell Alumni News., June 1918 (Box 10, Folder 66)
  - Talk at the Auburn Theological Seminary., Oct. 1918 (Box 10, Folder 67)
  - Address at the dinner of the Holland Society; Address at Cosmopolitan Club (21 Feb. 1919) on League of Nations., 16 Jan. 1919 (Box 10, Folder 68)
  - Address at the Semi-Centennial Celebration of Cornell University., 1919 (Box 10, Folder 69)
  - Speech at the Semi-Centennial Celebration dinner., 20 June 1919 (Box 10, Folder 70)
  - Speech at the unveiling of the statue of Ezra Cornell., 22 June 1919 (Box 10, Folder 71)
  - Manuscript draft: "Ezra Cornell", 23 June 1919 (Box 10, Folder 72)
  - Address to students: "We have come into a new world...", 2 Oct. 1919 (Box 10, Folder 73)
  - "The American University: To-Day and Tomorrow", 20 Jan. 1920 (Box 10, Folder 74)
  - Address at the Pan American Society., 27 Jan. 1920 (Box 10, Folder 75)
  - Address at Farmers' Week, New York State College of Agriculture., 12 Feb. 1920 (Box 10, Folder 76)
  - "As Reflected by..." in Japan Through the Eyes of..., ca. 1920 (Box 10, Folder 77)
  - "The American University: To-day and Tomorrow", Jan.-Feb. 1920 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Letter to the Board of Trustees of Cornell University; Schurman's resignation: "I have long been of the opinion...", 12 Feb. 1920 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - "The American University: To-day and Tomorrow", 19 Apr. 1920 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Address at Imperial University (Japan)., 28 Apr. 1920 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Commencement Address., 23 June 1920 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - "Liberty in the Present World Crisis", 27 June 1920 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - An "interview" with President-Elect Warren Harding., Nov. 1920 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Address before the American Chamber of Commerce at Tientsin: "Business Situation in the United States", 13 Oct. 1921 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - "Vast Changes in China", 1921 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Address before the American Association of North China on Washington's Birthday., 22 Feb. 1922 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - "What the Washington Conference has done for China", 22 Feb. 1922 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - "Foreign Help and Self-help for China", 28 Mar. 1922 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - "The United States and the Philippines": "It is now twenty three years since I came to Manila...", Mar. 1922 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - "It is a great pleasure to me to meet in the capital of China so many of my countrymen...", 1922 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Speech before the American Association, Peking., 22 Feb. 1923 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Speech in Harbin China., 6 Sept. 1923 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Speech at dinner of Governor, Yunnan., 1923 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Speech to the American Association of North China: "George Washington was not born great...", 22 Feb. 1924 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Speech in presenting Dr. Tagore to the Anglo-American Association at the tiffin., 25 Apr. 1924 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - "The Immigration Problem in the United States", 14 May 1924 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Speech at the Luncheon of the Chamber of Commerce of San Francisco., 5 Sept. 1924 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Speech before the Union Club of Shanghai., 17 Dec. 1924 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - "Extraterritoriality and its Gradual Relinquishment", 20 Jan. 1925 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Speech at the dinner of the American Association in Celebration of Washington's Birthday., 23 Feb. 1925 (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Speech in Berlin: "In these hours Americans everywhere, whether at home or abroad, are coming together to celebrate...", 4 July 1926 (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - "Kant: The Champion of American Independence", 1926 (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - "Ansprachen Tischreden und Telegrammwechsel bei der Eröffnung der Direkten Kabellinie Emden-Azoren New York", 4 Mar. 1927 (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - Speech on the occasion of the dedication of the Emden-Azores Cable., 4 Mar. 1927 (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - Speech at the Centennial Celebration of the Foundation of Bremerhaven., 30 Apr. 1927 (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - Incomplete typescript: "I said something this morning regarding the earliest navigation and commerce...", 1927 (Box 11, Folder 30)
  - "I am deeply sensible of the honor...", May 1927 (Box 11, Folder 31)
  - "Heute morgen habe ich ueber die Anfaenge der Schiffahrt...", 1927 (Box 11, Folder 32)
  - "Es ist mire eine besondere Freude...", 1927 (Box 11, Folder 33)
  - "Ich bin, wie Sie sehen, auf der Reise...", 1927 (Box 11, Folder 34)
  - "We are assembled to celebrate the foundation of Bremerhaven...", ca. 1927 (Box 11, Folder 35)
  - "It gives me particular pleasure to be able to be with you...", 1927 (Box 11, Folder 36)
  - "I am, as you will recognize, a traveller, but I am happy to accept...", 1927 (Box 11, Folder 37)
  - Welcome by Ambassador Schurman at Tempelhofer Feld: "Welcome to the aviator who has made the first non-stop flight from New York to Germany...", 7 June 1927 (Box 11, Folder 38)
  - Speech at the banquet given by the Reichsverkehrsminister: "I desire to thank you for your splendid tribute to the two young Americans...", 9 June 1927 (Box 11, Folder 39)
  - Speech at the Rathaus: "The people of Berlin, and indeed of all Germany...", 10 June 1927 (Box 11, Folder 40)
  - Speech at Dinner Given by American Club in Honor of Mssrs. Chamberlin and Levine: "The German people have extended to Chamberlin and Levine such a hearty..."English and German texts., 10 June 1927 (Box 11, Folder 41)
  - "Wir Amerikaner freuen uns in Deutschland...""Es ist mir eine besondere Freude...""It affords me an especial pleasure to be allowed to take part at this memorable celebration, and I would like to express my appreciation to the German Shakespeare Society...", 10 June 1927 (Box 11, Folder 42)
  - Article for the "Paris Herald" Special Edition: "On this day in 1776 the American nation was born...", 4 July 1927 (Box 11, Folder 43)
  - "Personal and Strictly Confidential for the Secretary": "I returned to Berlin Saturday morning...", 25 July 1927 (Box 11, Folder 44)
  - "I am delighted to see you again...", 13 Aug. 1927 (Box 11, Folder 45)
  - An Appreciation of Baron Maltzan., Sept. 1927 (Box 11, Folder 46)
  - "When the American aviator, Chamberlin, and his companion, Levine...", ca. 1927 (Box 11, Folder 47)
  - "We are met today to commemorate the arrival in America of Baron Wilhelm von Steuben...", 3 Nov. 1927 (Box 11, Folder 48)
  - Press dispatch: "The American Ambassador in Berlin expressed himself...", 29 Nov. 1927 (Box 11, Folder 49)
  - "Während des Krieges und in der ersten Nachkriegszeit...", ca. 1927 (Box 11, Folder 50)
  - Translation by Schurman: "Old Heidelberg dear city...", ca. 1927 (Box 11, Folder 51)
  - "Address" at the Ceremony Conferring Honorary Degrees upon the Foreign Minister Dr. Stresemann and the Ambassador of the United States in the Convocation Hall of Heidelberg University., 1928 (Box 11, Folder 52)
  - Address at the banquet of the American Club of Berlin in honor of the Trans-Atlantic flyers., 2 May 1928 (Box 11, Folder 53)
  - Remarks on the occasion of receiving the honorary degree of Doctor of Philosophy from the University of Heidelberg., 5 May 1928 (Box 11, Folder 54)
  - "Ich bin mir der Ehre voll bewusst...", May 1928 (Box 11, Folder 55)
  - Speech at the dinner in honor of the Arctic flyers, Captain Wilkins and Lieutenant Eielson., 31 May 1928 (Box 11, Folder 56)
  - Address at the Hochschule für Politik, Berlin., 10 Aug. 1928 (Box 11, Folder 57)
  - Address on the occasion of the christening of the North German Lloyd's Steamship EUROPA., 15 Aug. 1928 (Box 11, Folder 58)
  - Remarks on the Subject of the Prevention of War., Aug. 1928 (Box 11, Folder 59)
  - Speech before the New York Chamber of Commerce., 1 Nov. 1928 (Box 11, Folder 60)
  - "Speech delivered in snow-storm from Balcony of Stadt Halle...""Es freut mich diesen langen...", 17 Dec. 1928 (Box 11, Folder 61)
  - "You have announced that the City of Heidelberg has conferred upon me honorary citizenship...", Dec. 1928 (Box 11, Folder 62)
  - "It is a delight once more to be in Heidelberg...", ca. Dec. 1928 (Box 11, Folder 63)
  - "Having just returned from Heidelberg to Berlin...", Dec. 1928 (Box 11, Folder 64)
  - Speech at the Washington's Birthday Dinner of the American Club in Berlin., 22 Feb. 1929 (Box 11, Folder 65)
  - "On the occasion of the celebration of Washington's Birthday...", 27 Feb. 1929 (Box 11, Folder 66)
  - "... des hundertsten Geburtstages von Carl Schurz...", 3 Mar. 1929 (Box 11, Folder 67)
  - "American Universities", 3 May 1929 (Box 11, Folder 68)
  - Address at the Dedication of the Harnack House of the Kaiser Wilhelm Gesellschaft for the Advancement of Science. English and German texts., 7 May 1929 (Box 11, Folder 69)
  - "Ansprachen bei der Einweihung des Harnak-Hauses", 7 May 1929 (Box 11, Folder 70)
  - Speech on the occasion of the Celebration of the 25th anniversary of the Kant-Gesellschaft at Halle., 22 May 1929 (Box 11, Folder 71)
  - Speech on the occasion of the Celebration of the 25th anniversary of the Kant-Gesellschaft at Halle. German text., 22 May 1929 (Box 11, Folder 72)
  - Speech on the occasion of the 100th Anniversary of the Opening of the American Consulate in Frankfort., 4 June 1929 (Box 11, Folder 73)
  - "China's Financial Status and its Relation to the Present Political Situation", 8 June 1929 (Box 11, Folder 74)
  - Address at the German Ministry of Transportation., 1929 (Box 11, Folder 75)
  - Tacna-Arica Celebration: "I join you in the expression of supreme satisfaction that it has been possible for Chile and Peru...", 18 June 1929 (Box 11, Folder 76)
  - Speech at the International Banquet of World Advertising Convention., 12 Aug. 1929 (Box 11, Folder 77)
  - Address at Friedrichshafen on the occasion of the return of the "Graf Zeppelin" from its flight around the world., 5 Sept. 1929 (Box 11, Folder 78)
  - "I felicitate the 'New York Herald' on the laying of the corner-stone of its new building...", 1 Oct. 1929 (Box 11, Folder 79)
  - "Dr. Stresemann's death comes as a great shock, for in spite of grave illness our hopes painted for him an active and fruitful future...", 3 Oct. 1929 (Box 11, Folder 80)
  - "Enlarging Campus and Locating Buildings", Oct. 1929 (Box 11, Folder 81)
  - Address at the Annual Banquet of the American Chamber of Commerce in Germany., 10 Dec. 1929 (Box 11, Folder 82)
  - "For a Chamber of Commerce I consider the proceedings have assumed an extraordinarily personal character...", 10 Dec. 1929 (Box 11, Folder 83)
  - "Gramophone record text of remarks made by the Ambassador for record to preserve his voice": "As I am laying down the office of Ambassador of the United States to Germany...", 4 Jan. 1930 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - "Beim Verlassen der deutschen Gewässer ist es mir ein...", Jan. 1930 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Speech at the Lincoln Dinner of the National Republican Club., 12 Feb. 1930 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Speech at the Dinner of the Board of Trade for German-American Commerce., 17 Feb. 1930 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - "Address" at the Banquet at the Hotel Astor, from the German American Commerce Bulletin., 17 Feb. 1930 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Speech at the Dinner of the Economic Club of New York., 6 Mar. 1930 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Notes of speech to the German-American Organization, New York City., 17 Mar. 1930 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - "Fellow Cornellians: We are calling the roll tonight...", 1 Apr. 1930 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - "In the United States we continue to hear the parrot-like refrain...", Apr.-July 1930 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - "In the 'New York Times' of last Sunday, October 19th, Governor Roosevelt...", 1930 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Notes for Address: "Stresemann", 3 Oct. 1930 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Address at World Alliance for International Friendship: "The highest expression of goodwill...", 10 Nov. 1930 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - "A World Out of Joint", 28 Oct. 1931 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - "The Old and New Education", 11 Jan. 1932 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - "Balch dinner in my honor at Cal Tech.", 15 Jan. 1932 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Notes for Pasadena lecture course: "Washington Bicentennial; Farewell Address", 18 Jan. 1932 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Notes for lecture, California Institute of Technology, Pasadena: "Germany and her Problems", 20 Jan. 1932 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Notes for Associates dinner talk, Cal. Tech., 25 Jan. 1932 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - "Foreign Affairs - Why the Philippines Expect Independence", Jan. 1932 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - "Among the remarkable things which the older generations witnessed is the rapid growth of American cities...", Feb. 1932 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Address to Dinner of Lincoln Club., 12 Feb. 1932 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - "Napoleon to Metternich", Feb. 1932 (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - "The Growth of Municipal Activities", 15 Feb. 1932 (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - "Great Britain and her Imperial Problems", 17 Feb. 1932 (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - "Developments in the Sino-Japanese Situation", 27 Feb. 1932 (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - "The U. S. and the Philippines", 24 Feb. 1932 (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - Last half of Address at the 64th Commencement of Cornell University., 20 June 1932 (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - "I spent the summer in England and Scotland, and last winter in Southern California...", 4 Aug. 1932 (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - Radio address: "Philippine Independence", 16 Nov. 1932 (Box 12, Folder 29)
  - "Philippine Independence", 16 Nov. 1932 (Box 12, Folder 30)
  - "Germany: Its International Relations and Political Conditions", 7 Nov. 1932 (Box 12, Folder 31)
  - "Philippine Independence", 12 Dec. 1932 (Box 12, Folder 32)
  - Speech for the American Club, Cairo: "The German Election of March 5, 1933", 9 Mar. 1933 (Box 12, Folder 33)
  - "The Manchurian Question", 27 Mar. 1933 (Box 12, Folder 34)
  - Speech to the Rotary Club, Shanghai: "The United States and the Philippines", 28 Sept. 1933 (Box 12, Folder 35)
  - "Cultural Inspiration from Germany", July 1934 (Box 12, Folder 36)
  - "Rise of Hitlerism", 16 Oct. 1934 (Box 12, Folder 37)
  - "The Reign of Force in the World", 17 Jan. 1938 (Box 12, Folder 38)
  - "The Reign of Force in the World", 17 Jan. 1938 (Box 12, Folder 39)
  - "Czechoslovakia Etc", 1 Oct. 1938 (Box 12, Folder 40)
  - "This is a memorable day in the history of the Memorial Hospital...", 1939 (Box 12, Folder 41)
  - "No Third Term for Any President", ca. 1939 (Box 12, Folder 42)
  - "The defenders of the Third Term declare that an emergency now exists...", ca. 1939 (Box 12, Folder 43)
  - "Statement" before the Sub-Committee of the Senate Judiciary Committee on the Subject of Limitation of Tenure of Office of the President of the United States., 9 Sept. 1940 (Box 12, Folder 44)
  - "Statement" in US News., 7 Feb. 1941 (Box 12, Folder 45)
  - Statement: "Retention of Reserve Components and Selectees in Military Service Beyond Twelve Months", 24 July 1941 (Box 12, Folder 46)
  - "Statement" in US News., 21 Nov. 1941 (Box 12, Folder 47)
  - "Two Views of the State", n.d. (Box 12, Folder 48)
  - "Self-Activity in Education", n.d. (Box 12, Folder 49)
  - "Crossing and the Submarine Peril" (Box 12, Folder 50)
  - "I never miss an opportunity to come to this beautiful and romantic city..." (Box 12, Folder 51)
  - "Free Inquiry and Free Speech in Our Universities" (Box 12, Folder 52)
  - "Gustav Stresemann", n.d. (Box 12, Folder 53)
  - "The Problem of Territorial Expansion", n.d. (Box 12, Folder 54)
  - "The Constitution", n.d. (Box 12, Folder 55)
  - Speeches at the Centennial Celebration of the Foundation of Bremerhaven., 30 APRn.y. (Box 12, Folder 56)
  - "Lassen Sie uns mit der naheliegenden Frage beginnen..." (Box 12, Folder 57)